I'm going to lay in this shot and I want to show you something.
Now you can see from this angle the V, that's what we're looking for the V or, or what I want to say, the funnel.
The reason why again is if it rains tonight this, the rain that will hit here is going to run down this V towards the stone into the bucket.
The morning dew collects underneath it so this is why it's shaped the way it is as you can see the, the strong funnel V so if you have it like this you know you're in good shape.
The stones right over the, the slit and now let's, let me explain the whole theory behind all this work.
You ever hear of the green house effect?
When water is enclosed it creates this, this precipitation, this dew.
We have water like I showed you earlier in the ground here and when it, this tarp heats up it creates the green house effect and the dew from that water will start to form on the underneath of this V, V tarp, and funnel tarp.
As it accumulates more and more it'll make space, it'll actually push the, the, the dew into the bucket and more dew will start to accumulate on the tarp and it'll keep doing this process as more dew drips in there it creates more open space.
And more of that rain water heats up and creates more dew on the tarp so it's this constant cycle of the dew forms spills into the bucket.
More space is provided, more a, dew is created and it spills into the bucket.
And we all, like I said, we also have the top for the, a, the rain water.
So that's the whole theory behind the solar still.